Contact

Phone

8970670927

Email

rohithprasad0@gmail.com

Address

Bangalore, India

Education

Bachelor of Engineering

Vidya Vikas Institute of Engineering and Technology, Mysore, Karnataka, India

Skills

HTML 5

CSS 3

BOOTSTRAP 5

JAVA SCRIPT

REACT.JS

ES-6

REDUX

PYTHON

Language

ENGLISH

KANNADA

HINDI

Rohith Prasad H N

Front-end Developer

PROFILE

A Steel Detailer with 4.10 years of professional experience by using Tekla software & Front-end Developer with 1.2 years of professional experience. having enhanced knowledge in web technologies and Proficient with React. Looking to expand my technical skills and forge a successful path for both the company and my future

EXPERIENCE

2022 - 2023 [May-2022 to Till Present]Snipe Tech Pvt Ltd.

Snipe Tech Pvt Ltd is Providing world class IT based Service in Enterprise Solutions for the Technology Solutions covering Embedded Systems and System Software to its Global Clientele

○ 2021 - 2022 [Feb-2021 to Apr-2022]

Green Brook Engineering sevices Pvt Ltd.

Green Brook Engineering Services are steadily growing company serving the entire construction value chain. and provide architectural drafting, engineering design, connection design, 3D Modeling, Building Information Modeling (BIM), steel detailing and offshore derrick modeling.

○ 2017 - 2021 [May-2017 to Jan-2022]

DGS Technical Sevices Pvt Ltd.

DGS Technical Services is a leading Engineering Services Provider since 2004 and covers several areas of Structural, Mechanical and Design Services for a variety of industrial and commercial requirements. Structural Steel Detailing.

ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES

- Worked on both static and dynamic website.
- developing the web pages using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Java Script(js), React JS, Redux. Having knowledge about react hooks, jsx ,js worked on crud operation.
- Methodologies -Agile, Scrum .
- version control-Bit-bucket, GitHub Used GIT and JIRA for defect tracking.
- used package mangers npm, node js ,linters as prettier, modules bundlers as web-pack

PROJECTS

1. Automated real estate solution (ARS) [Oct 2021-Till Present]

Automated real estate solutions is a automated online transparent platform fro real estate process, it provide services such as Buying, Selling, Rent, and Lease of Agricultural, Residential, Industrial and Commercial properties through active and genuine agents.

Module Worked:

About page, Agent Page, Agent dash board page, seller page, Seller dashboard page, Buyer page, Buyer dashboard, Theme changes.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Using the knowledge of web Technologies HTML5,
 CSS3, Bootstrap 5, built the structure styling to achieve the required outcome.
- Worked on CRUD operations and functionality of the services using the knowledge of programming languages.

- Used the json as the temporary database to work on CRUD operations.
- Work closely with design ,product management and development teams to create elegant usable, responsive and interactive across multiple devices.
- Review and optimise the app usage by monitoring key metrics and rectifiying the issue proactively.
- Implement and advance UI/UX in React.JS with high quality.
- Implement creative web application with modern/interactive design

2. Live Stock Management System(LMS)

[Jun 2021-Sep 2021]

The platform is an e-commerce website which helps in Buying and Selling of the farm Animals and the fresh meat of the farm Animals to door Step

Module Worked:

About page, Home page, Cart Design

Roles and Responsibilities

- Using the knowledge of web technologies ,HTML 5, CSS 3,Bootstrap 5,built the structure and styling to achieve the required outcome Building the website with react framework.
- Worked on CRUD operations and functionality of the services using the knowledge of programming languages.
- Design ,configure, code and test the appropriate level of customization that are identified , reviewed and allowed within the project scope and budget.
- Strong understanding of REST APIs and knowledge of how to interface with them building stable and maintainable code base using react